{
  "theme": [
    {
      "Questions": {
        "theme": [
          {
            "Question": "Who was the first Disney princess?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Snow White",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Cinderella",
              "Ariel",
              "Belle"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Snow White, from the 1937 film 'Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs,' was the first Disney princess."
          },
          {
            "Question": "What is the name of the sailor man who loves spinach?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Popeye",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Bluto",
              "Olive Oyl",
              "Wimpy"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Popeye is a famous cartoon character known for his strength gained from eating spinach."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which historical figure do the cartoon characters Pinky and the Brain try to take over the world like?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Napoleon",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Julius Caesar",
              "Cleopatra",
              "Genghis Khan"
            ],
            "Explanation": "The cartoon characters Pinky and the Brain try to take over the world like Napoleon Bonaparte."
          },
          {
            "Question": "What is the name of the famous rabbit who appears in 'What's Opera, Doc?'?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Bugs Bunny",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Daffy Duck",
              "Elmer Fudd",
              "Sylvester"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Bugs Bunny is a well-known cartoon character who often appears alongside Elmer Fudd in Looney Tunes."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which cartoon character is famous for saying \"I tawt I taw a puddy tat!\"?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Tweety Bird",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Sylvester",
              "Daffy Duck",
              "Porky Pig"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Tweety Bird, often pursued by Sylvester the cat, is known for this catchphrase."
          },
          {
            "Question": "In 'The Flintstones', what is the name of the Flintstones' pet dinosaur?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Dino",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Rex",
              "Barney",
              "Spike"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Dino is the Flintstones' pet dinosaur who acts like a dog and often gets Fred into trouble."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which cartoon featured a group of crime-solving teenagers and their talking dog?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Scooby-Doo",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "The Smurfs",
              "Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles",
              "The Jetsons"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Scooby-Doo and the Mystery Gang travel in the Mystery Machine and solve mysteries with clever disguises and traps."
          },
          {
            "Question": "What town does SpongeBob SquarePants live in?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Bikini Bottom",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Bikini Atoll",
              "SpongeBobville",
              "Krusty Krab"
            ],
            "Explanation": "SpongeBob SquarePants lives in the underwater city of Bikini Bottom, known for its colorful characters and adventures."
          },
          {
            "Question": "What are the names of the two mice in the cartoon 'Pinky and the Brain'?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Pinky and Brain",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Tom and Jerry",
              "Itchy and Scratchy",
              "Chip and Dale"
            ],
            "Explanation": "'Pinky and the Brain' features two laboratory mice, one highly intelligent and the other dim-witted, who seek to take over the world."
          },
          {
            "Question": "What is the catchphrase of the cartoon character Homer Simpson?",
            "TrueAnswer": "D'oh!",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Ay caramba!",
              "Mmm...donuts",
              "Cowabunga!"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Homer Simpson's catchphrase 'D'oh!' is often exclaimed when he makes a mistake or experiences frustration."
          },
          {
            "Question": "What is the name of the futuristic family in 'The Jetsons'?",
            "TrueAnswer": "The Jetsons",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "The Flintstones",
              "The Incredibles",
              "The Robots"
            ],
            "Explanation": "'The Jetsons' is a futuristic cartoon series featuring the Jetson family, living in Orbit City in the year 2062."
          },
          {
            "Question": "In 'Pokémon', what is the name of Ash Ketchum's first Pokémon?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Pikachu",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Charmander",
              "Squirtle",
              "Bulbasaur"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Pikachu, an Electric-type Pokémon, is Ash Ketchum's first and most loyal Pokémon partner."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which cartoon character resides in a pineapple under the sea?",
            "TrueAnswer": "SpongeBob SquarePants",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Patrick Star",
              "Squidward Tentacles",
              "Mr. Krabs"
            ],
            "Explanation": "SpongeBob SquarePants, an eternally optimistic sea sponge, lives in a pineapple under the sea in Bikini Bottom."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Who is known for seeking the lost city of gold in the cartoon 'DuckTales'?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Scrooge McDuck",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Huey Duck",
              "Dewey Duck",
              "Louie Duck"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Scrooge McDuck, the wealthy and adventurous duck, leads his nephews on treasure-hunting adventures to find the lost city of gold."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which cartoon character always yells 'I'm coming to join you, Elizabeth!'?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Fred Sanford",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Bugs Bunny",
              "Popeye",
              "SpongeBob SquarePants"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Fred Sanford, from the cartoon 'Sanford and Son,' often comically yells this line in response to stress or surprise."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Who is the archenemy of the Powerpuff Girls?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Mojo Jojo",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Him",
              "Fuzzy Lumpkins",
              "Princess Morbucks"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Mojo Jojo is a highly intelligent and evil chimpanzee, serving as the archenemy of the Powerpuff Girls in the animated series."
          },
          {
            "Question": "In 'The Simpsons', what is the name of Ned Flanders' business?",
            "TrueAnswer": "The Leftorium",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Flanders' Furniture",
              "Neighborly Knick-Knacks",
              "Flanders' Fix-Its"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Ned Flanders' store, The Leftorium, sells left-handed products and becomes an enduring part of 'The Simpsons' lore."
          },
          {
            "Question": "What is the name of the group of babies in 'Rugrats'?",
            "TrueAnswer": "The Rugrats",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "The Muppet Babies",
              "The Smurflings",
              "The Baby Bears"
            ],
            "Explanation": "'Rugrats' follows the adventures of a group of babies, Tommy, Chuckie, and more, as they explore the world around them."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which cartoon series chronicles the adventures of a time-traveling dog and his human companion?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Mr. Peabody & Sherman",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Dora the Explorer",
              "Blue's Clues",
              "The Magic School Bus"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Mr. Peabody, a genius dog, and Sherman, his adopted son, use their time machine to go on historical adventures."
          },
          {
            "Question": "In 'Rocky and Bullwinkle', what is the name of the incompetent spies pursuing the moose and squirrel?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Boris and Natasha",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Spyder and Morgana",
              "Rollo and Marge",
              "Fritz and Hilda"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Boris Badenov and Natasha Fatale are the comically inept spies depicted in 'The Rocky and Bullwinkle Show'."
          }
        ]
      }
    }
  ]
}